Vanessa Azenwa Shiundu

vanessa.azenwa@gmail.com / +254717400821 / Nairobi, Kenya

Summary

Title: Fullstack Software Developer

I am a talented Junior Software Engineer trained to work with customers, team members and project leaders to accomplish software engineering and updating tasks according to timelines.

With a solid understanding of full development lifecycle, skilled to work with front and back-end technologies to produce and evaluate projects, I look forward to joining a dynamic team and contribute towards providing creative solutions and making the world a better place; one day at a time.

In addition, I have industry specific training and experience in IT, Statistics and Finance. View <u>My LinkedIn Profile</u>, <u>My GitHub Profile</u> and my <u>Portfolio</u> for a glimpse of some applications and websites I have built over this year.

Skills

Django, Flask, Python, Flutter, WordPress, Angular, React, Google Cloud Platform, CSS3, JavaScript, APIs, Git, Databases, PostgreSQL

Experience

Developer - Intern

Greenspoon Kenya Itd • Nairobi, Nairobi County

10/2022 - Present

- Responsible for both back-end and front-end development of the organization's existing website including the implementation of WordPress plugins and custom functionality. This is as required by internal and external stakeholders.
- Monitoring website availability and performing regular maintenance / upgrades on WordPress plugins and core.
- Conducting website performance tests
- Troubleshooting issues
- Performing regular plugin, theme and core updates and resolving issues in Staging environment before transferring changes to Live
- Train internal teams as required
- Proactively monitoring website performance and availability and suggesting solutions to improve speed, performance & optimizations

Software Engineering

01/2022 - Present

- Efficient collaboration with team members and leading a number of projects as SCRUM MASTER.
- Designing the structure of websites and apps, optimizing for mobile devices
- Creating the logic that instructs applications on how to interpret user input and what feedback to give the user after executing the submitted request I achieved this by creating algorithms that fetch and manipulate data stored in database systems mainly using python, Flask, Django, Flutter, React and SQL.
- Developing app integration with REST APIs for google maps, social media authentication, movie APIs and other services.
- Proficient in Git and Git-hub for version control
- · Managing time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades
- Planning, writing and debugging web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Reliever Church Accountant

Nairobi East SDA Church

11/2021 - 12/2021

Finance Assistant

Vivo Energy Kenya 03/2019 - 03/2020

Intern cum Retail Stations Assistant

Engen Kenya Itd 04/2017 - 02/2019

Education

Software Engineering

Moringa School • Nairobi 07/2022

Diploma in Business and Accounting

ACCA 10/2016

Digital Marketing

Google and Livity Africa 06/2015

Dlploma in French

Alliance Française de Nairobi 11/2014

Statistics and Statistical Packages

University of Nairobi 10/2013

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

St. Theresea's Eregi 11/2011 A-

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

St. Teresa's Isanjiro 11/2007 A

Languages

English, French, Swahili

1. Aleeda Fazal,

CTO - Chief Technology Officer,

Greenspoon Kenya ltd

2. Stanley Njuru,

Treasurer,

Vivo Energy Kenya ltd.

3. Philip Migire,

Treasurer - Nairobi East SDA,

• Contact details available upon request